Win or lose, always aim high.
Eddie the Eagle is a comedy, drama, history film directed by Dexter Fletcher.
The feel-good story of Michael 'Eddie' Edwards, an unlikely but courageous British ski-jumper who
never stopped believing in himself—even as an entire nation was counting him out.
With the help of a rebellious and charismatic coach, Eddie takes on the establishment and wins the hearts of sports
fans around the world by making an improbable and historic showing at the 1988 Calgary Winter Olympics.
Eddie Edwards, played by Taron Egerton.
Bronson Peary, played by Hugh Jackman.
Warren Sharp, played by Christopher Walken.
Carrie, played by Ania Sowinski.
Erik Moberg, played by Mads Sjøgård Pettersen.
Petra, played by Iris Berben.
Eddie the Eagle is a 2015 biographical sports
comedy-drama film directed by Dexter Fletcher.
The film stars Taron Egerton as Michael "Eddie the Eagle" Edwards, a British skier who in 1988 became
the first competitor to represent Great Britain in Olympic ski jumping since 1928.
Hugh Jackman, Christopher Walken, Iris Berben and Jim Broadbent co-star.
The film had its first public screening at the Butt-Numb-A-Thon in Austin, Texas on December 12,
2015 and its world premiere at the 2016 Sundance Film Festival on January 26, 2016.
The film was released in the United States on February 26, 2016, by 20th Century
Fox and in the United Kingdom on March 28, 2016, by Lionsgate.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and in 2017 it
was nominated for the Empire Award for Best British Film.
The film explores themes of underdog, sports, olympic games, mountain, ski jump.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting and emotional.